https://anuraganalog.github.io/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/peddianurag-01767a166/

# **ANURAG PEDDI**

+1 (703) 459-6402 apeddi@gmu.edu github.com/AnuragAnalog

#### **PROFILE**

As an undergraduate with a passion for machine learning and data science, I have experience understanding and analysing data to drive growth. Provide the necessary insights, analytics, and visualisation to aid decision-making for a finance and fashion forecasting company. I worked as a teaching assistant under my supervisor during my final semester.

### **EDUCATION**

**George Mason University** 

Fairfax, VA

Aug 2022 - May 2024 (Expected)

- M.S. in Computer Science
- **Graduate Coursework:** Analysis of Algorithms, Data Mining, Database Management Concepts and Systems, Software Engineering, Computer Systems.

**University of Hyderabad** 

Hyderabad, India

July 2017 - Aug 2022

- Int.M.Tech. in Computer Science, GPA: 3.78
- **Graduate Coursework:** Algorithms, Operating Systems, Databases, Software Engineering, Neural Networks, Pattern Recognition.

Intermediate Hyderabad, India July 2015 – July 2017

• High School in Maths Physics Chemistry, Percentage: 98.3%

#### INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Intern Stylumia, Bangalore

May 2021 - June 2022

- Made an Intuitive Covid19 Prediction model for India's third wave.
- Building Custom ETL pipelines, Optimization of Inventory Allocation and Pipelines for hyperparameter tuning of ML models on real-time data
- Build some time-series models using modern frameworks, converted data into actionable insights by predicting and modelling future outcomes
- I have also secured the Employee of the Month Award(April 2022) for my work in interpretability of demand forecasting algorithms.

**Machine Learning Intern** 

Grroom, Bombay

October 2020 - December 2020

- As an Intern, My tasks were Image Scraping, Model building, and Model tuning for object detection(Yolo) in Fashion Domain to yield good mAP and accuracy.
- I have also researched cost-effective ways of deploying multiple models on the web and suggested them on AWS.

Intern CMI, Chennai May 2019 - June 2019

- Using Random forests and SVM, I created a machine-learning model to predict whether the price will rise or fall.
- Learned about financial statistics, Markov chains, portfolio optimization etc.

### **SKILLS**

- Hard Skills: C, Python, R, ReactJS, JavaScript, MySQL, Java, MongoDB, Power BI, Tableau, TensorFlow, Flask, Git
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Problem-Solving, Time Management

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## **One Class Classifiers and IoT GANs**

UoH, Hyderabad

August 2021 - August 2022

- My final year thesis includes building a GAN which can generate new attacks which are not yet known.
- Along with that, I have designed a One Class Classifier which detects the new synthesized attacks.

## Pen Ink Differentiation using CNN

**IDRBT**, Hyderabad

November 2020 - April 2021

Built a state-of-the-art CNN model(siamese network) to solve the fraud detection problem in Handwriting Forgery.

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

• Online Video Streaming Using LAMP Stack, I created an online video streaming website where the admin may add videos to be seen by users. MySQL stores all user and video information.

- Try Every ML Algorithm A Playground where you may experiment with various machine learning algorithms on a given dataset by tinkering with its hyper-parameters until you get bored.
- Twitter Data Sentiment Analysis COVID19 Twitter Data Analysis, Indian Sentiment Analysis Using Tweets after Three Lockdowns
- A GUI based Path finding algorithm using Backtracking In this, the program generates a random maze of nxn dimension, which will be solved by the backtracking method.
- Many more projects which include ML and DL Concepts Android, web, and IoT integration (for example, object detection, gender and age prediction etc.)

## **MOOC COURSES**

#### Tableau Fundamentals DataCamp March 2021 – April 2021

• I have gained a comprehensive introduction to data analysis and visual design in Tableau. From single worksheets to

## **TensorFlow Developer Professional**

Coursera

April 2020 - June 2020

• This is a foundational course which taught made me zero to hero in TensorFlow. I have learned the necessary tools to build scalable AI-powered applications with TensorFlow.

## **Deep Learning Specialization**

Coursera

03/2020 - May 2020

• It is a foundational program that will help you understand the capabilities, challenges, and consequences of deep learning and prepare you to participate in the development of leading-edge AI technology.

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- Smart India Hackathon Shortlisted for Smart India Hackathon, Automated Land use classification based on Multispectral Imagery using the DL model
- Amazon Machine Learning Challenge Created a MultiClass classification model for a large corpus, which gives comparable accuracy to state-of-the-art models.
- HackNITP 3.0 Built an audio sentiment predictor and secured  $5^{th}$  Place in the Al Domain.

### **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND AWARDS**

- Volunteer@IEEE Hyderabad Section I also competed in the IEEEXtreme 13.0 24-hour coding competition during my volunteer time.
- **Volunteer@Green Revolution** Volunteer for the Green Revolution Program by ICCE, 2017; during my volunteering time, I lead a campaign for NO GLOBAL WARMING on my campus.
- Mess secretary@University of Hyderabad During my undergraduate, I was a mess secretary for a semester; my roles
  included organising the food schedule, guiding the workers, managing all the financial parts, and sometimes serving
  the food.